<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Actionable Insights</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Actionable Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 20:34:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Dr Paul Hewson PhD CStat CSci Paul has had a wide range of roles across private and public sector. As an academic, he was awarded a highly prestigious National Teaching Fellowship as a result of his commitment to communicating statistical thinking. He has done a wide variety of consulting work and most recently has worked as a Senior Data Scientist in a start-up and now works as a Business Intelligence Specialist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actionable Insight</title>
      <link>/sections/insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/insight/</guid>
      <description>The question nowadays is not &amp;ldquo;do we have data&amp;rdquo;. Often the first question is &amp;ldquo;do we have the right data?&amp;rdquo; Even if the answer to this question is &amp;ldquo;NO&amp;rdquo;, we often need to be able to do the best we can to answer the question &amp;ldquo;what insights can we gain from this answer&amp;rdquo;?
(I would have used the acronym AI for Actionable Insight but that acronym has been taken)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Data Science</title>
      <link>/sections/modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/modern/</guid>
      <description>Modern Data Science requires a modern IT environment. However, it also requires an up to date knowledge of what is possible in statistical science. The field of statistical science is being advanced just as rapidly as any other science. Many statistics courses are based on techniques which were invented before 1930, and training has not been updated. Given the availability of powerful computers, convenient analytical methods are no longer needed to approximate a solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reported Road Injuries in GB</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-08-07-stats19overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-08-07-stats19overview/</guid>
      <description>In the event of a road collision involving at least one vehicle and one injury, there is a requirement in the UK to report to the police within 30 days. The data are called “STATs19” after the form on which the data are collected, and are made available as “Open Data” for anyone to analyse.
This immediately raises a number of points:
What is a “road” collision (do car parks, driveways, private roads count)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Data</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-08-06-data_insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-08-06-data_insights/</guid>
      <description>Having worked as an academic, as a Data Scientist, as a Business Intelligence Specialist as well as doing a lot of consulting I have learnt a lot about the way we use data, and the way people perceive &amp;ldquo;statistics&amp;rdquo; (whatever that word really means).
Sometimes, a problem is so straightforward it only requires technical input (data processing) and it&amp;rsquo;s solved. More often though, a lot more interpretation is needed. Often, the problem is not so much about the &amp;ldquo;statistics&amp;rdquo; but about the study design.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>