<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Insights for Action</title>
    <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Insights for Action</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 15:36:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://insightsforaction.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/about/</guid>
      <description>Dr Paul Hewson PhD CStat CSci Paul has had a wide range of roles across private and public sector. As an academic, he was awarded a highly prestigious National Teaching Fellowship as a result of his commitment to communicating statistical thinking. He has done a wide variety of consulting work and most recently has worked as a Senior Data Scientist in a start-up and now works as a Business Intelligence Specialist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actionable Insight</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/sections/insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/sections/insight/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, we rarely ask the question &amp;ldquo;do we have data&amp;rdquo;. Often we have lots of data and the first barrier we hit may force us to instead ask &amp;ldquo;do we have the right data?&amp;rdquo; Even when the answer to this question is NO, we often need to be able to do the best we can with the available data. It has become so easy to collect vast quantities of electronic data as a byproduct of other processes that we expect data to be on tap and free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Data Science</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/sections/modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/sections/modern/</guid>
      <description>There are two key things to say about modern Data Science.
Continuous Improvement / Continuous Delivery The first concerns &amp;ldquo;Continous Integration/Continuous Delivery&amp;rdquo; (CI/CD); a modern software development practice. The advantages of scripted analyses (reproducibility, testing, auditability) are well established; it&amp;rsquo;s a small leap to seeing these scripts as simple pieces of software and realising they need their entire architecture specified and tested continuously. Indeed I have published in Annals of Operations Research on the pitfalls of spreadsheets for data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some ansible woes</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12-18_ansible_woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 15:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12-18_ansible_woes/</guid>
      <description>Anonymous from Pinterest
After some 12 years, I had to set up a new machine for my own use. I bought a reconditioned HP with around 16Gb RAM, 500Gb SSD. It came with a Windows OS, which I was going to wipe out. However, for various reasons (mainly some wonderful animation apps I use in teaching which require Mac or Windows only and need access to the sound system) I decided to keep the Windows host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github actions</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12-14_github_actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 15:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12-14_github_actions/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Oleg Magni from Pexels
I know this seems like a tiny problem compared to everything else that has happened in 2020. But I started the year having learnt how to use Travis CI. This meant I could put my hobby projects under some kind of continuous testing. Now, whatever the merits of various workflows that can used for CI, Travis was supported by the R community. It was well integrated into R package development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software capital</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12_01_api_contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 11:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12_01_api_contracts/</guid>
      <description>David Sankel CppCon 2016 presentation &amp;ldquo;Building Software Capital&amp;rdquo;
Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been updating my C++ skills. In the far past, I&amp;rsquo;ve used it to speed up algorithms in scripted languages. However, I have never used it as a standalone programming language. And when I say C++ I think I really mean C, I just happen to compile it with g++. Currently, I have a couple of problems which might change my limited exposure and get me much deeper in C++ code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflicts between Agile and Data Modelling</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-11-25_agile_and_data_modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 10:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-11-25_agile_and_data_modelling/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Christina Morillo from Pexels
Having worked in various Agile and Waterfall environments I have become fascinated by the potential mismatch between Data Modelling and Agile. Searching for some discussion pieces on this, I found an interesting post that reviews a conference discussion. Ultimately, this dates from Enterprise Data World 2015, but does seem to draw on a lot of expertise from enterprise level people who have had to reconcile Data Modelling and Agile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unreasonable effectiveness of data</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-11-16_unreasonable_effectiveness_of_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 10:37:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-11-16_unreasonable_effectiveness_of_data/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Christina Morillo from Pexels
In 1960, Eugene Wigner published &amp;ldquo;The unreasonable effectiveness of mathematics in the natural sciences&amp;rdquo;. Many commentators have indeed agreed it is surprising how relatively simple maths can indeed model so much of the natural world. Wigner argued that modelling a given scientific theory can lead to further advances in the theory. He also claimed success in that a mathematical model can make predictions which allow the theory to be empirically tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GB Road Fatalities and Life Expectancy</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-09-07-road_fatalities_life_expectancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-09-07-road_fatalities_life_expectancy/</guid>
      <description>In total, over the four decades for which we have data (1979-2018), 147,562 fatalities have been reported to the police. Whilst it is the case that the number of reported fatalities has reduced considerably:
 In 2018, 1,784 fatalities were reported. This still feels like a substantial tragedy and many argue there is considerable potential to reduce this much further if we took the decisions (such as limiting urban speeds) to make roads safer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration management</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020_09-03_ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020_09-03_ansible/</guid>
      <description>One thing I have learnt is configuration management. It&amp;rsquo;s an under-rated aspect of reproducible research. I was quickly experimenting with an R package, but needed to install the sf package on my tinkering machine. That in turn required another R package units. And in turn, units needed some header files, as did sf. As it turns out, units package failed with a very nice error message telling me exactly what I had to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Sources and Cycling</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-09-03_data_sources_on_cyling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-09-03_data_sources_on_cyling/</guid>
      <description>Something I&amp;rsquo;ve been droning on about for a few years concerns our reluctance to use datasets that already exist.
  Specifically in relation to cycling, we have a lot of data on cycling that is rarely used, and that&amp;rsquo;s without worrying about data that aren&amp;rsquo;t disseminated in a way that lets us use it. Here are some high quality UK based data sources. These come from surveys that are very expensive to conduct:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy by Design</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-09-02_privacy_by_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 10:37:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-09-02_privacy_by_design/</guid>
      <description>Photo Credit: Photo by ThisIsEngineering from Pexels
Legislation which carries large fines usually provides a good reason for checking out the law. In this case, the driver is the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), an EU directive which addresses the fundamental rights and freedoms of natural persons. Natural persons are &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; people, unlike llegal persons which includes entities like companies. It asserts that natural persons have the right to have their personal data personal data protected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Websites with Hugo and R-Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-08-18-hugo_blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-08-18-hugo_blogdown/</guid>
      <description>The current iteration of this website is a static website based on Hugo. In my opinion, there is a lot to like about static websites. I have previously used Jekyll and once upon a time coded html manually. However, modern static website generators allow a wonderful presentation. The currently styling is based upon the Terrassa theme; for me it scored highly for accessibility and mobile friendliness. The bigger issue for me though is to do data and version controlling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reported Road Injuries in GB</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-08-07-stats19overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-08-07-stats19overview/</guid>
      <description>In the event of a road collision involving at least one vehicle and one injury, there is a requirement in the UK to report to the police within 30 days. The data are called “STATs19” after the form on which the data are collected, and are made available as “Open Data” for anyone to analyse.
This immediately raises a number of points:
What is a “road” collision (do car parks, driveways, private roads count)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Data</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-08-06-data_insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-08-06-data_insights/</guid>
      <description>Photo credit: Vojtech Okenka from Pexels
Having worked as an academic, as a Data Scientist, as a Business Intelligence Specialist as well as doing a lot of consulting I have learnt a lot about the way we use data, and the way people perceive &amp;ldquo;statistics&amp;rdquo; (whatever that word really means).
Sometimes, a problem is so straightforward it only requires technical input (data processing) and it&amp;rsquo;s solved. More often though, a lot more interpretation is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical models and statistical models</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-08-12_math_or_stat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2020-08-12_math_or_stat/</guid>
      <description>I suppose I started thinking about this really hard in the early days of the COVID-19 pandemic. I’m not sure it’s something we articulate well; the difference between a mathematical model. A mathematical model is meant to capture the science of a phenomenon in mathematical terms. A statistical model is meant to “fit” data and account for the uncertainty; but doesn’t necessarily explain the science. And there are certainly plenty of examples where you’re fitting a statistical model to estimate the parameters of a mathematical model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The right tech for the job</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-07-05_the_right_tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-07-05_the_right_tech/</guid>
      <description>A small trebuchet in action
This Trebuchet is a bit puny compared to the one at Warwick Castle. But it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating piece of engineering, and certainly makes a bit of a difference from doing bisections with a compass. Here&amp;rsquo;s why I selected this as &amp;ldquo;the right tech&amp;rdquo; to use in school outreach work.
This is old work now, but I learnt a lot getting involved in it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>