<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data ethics and governance on Insights for Action</title>
    <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tags/data-ethics-and-governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data ethics and governance on Insights for Action</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 08:04:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://insightsforaction.uk/tags/data-ethics-and-governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the Post Office Horizon Enquiry</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2024-05-23-post_office_horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 08:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2024-05-23-post_office_horizon/</guid>
      <description>/home/phewson/Documents/blog_source/static/en/posts/2024-05-23-post_office_horizon/pexels-cameron-readius-2648348-4223084.jpg
Photo by Cameron Readius from Pexels
I can&amp;rsquo;t pretend I had read Rebecca Thomson&amp;rsquo;s article &amp;ldquo;Bankruptcy, prosecution and disrupted livelihoods – postmasters tell their story&amp;rdquo; in May 2009 in Computer Weekly, but certainly through journalism such as Private Eye I was aware well before the ITV drama screened in 2024.
Therefore, I&amp;rsquo;m most surprised by the evidence presented by Paula Vennells at the Statuary Inquiry on May 22nd. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get into an appraisal of her credibility or her competence, other than to wonder how much media coverage you can dismiss and still do your job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Privacy; Disclosure control and differential privacy</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2021-08-05-disclosure_control_privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2021-08-05-disclosure_control_privacy/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Pixabay from Pexels
I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a lot about how Differential Privacy is the answer to all our privacy concerns. However, having probed the methodology in detail, I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure. Indeed, I think we have a silo problem. Differential Privacy has been developed in a Computer Science framework as a means of balancing the need for altering data to meet privacy requirements with the need to maintain data close enough to their raw state to yield meaningful answers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
