<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data ethics and governance on Insights for Action</title>
    <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tags/data-ethics-and-governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data ethics and governance on Insights for Action</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 08:04:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://insightsforaction.uk/tags/data-ethics-and-governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the Post Office Horizon Enquiry</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2024-05-23-post_office_horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 08:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2024-05-23-post_office_horizon/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Cameron Readius from Pexels
I won&amp;rsquo;t be the only person who has been reading about the Post Office Horizon scandal ever since Rebecca Thomson wrote about it in May 2009 in Computer Weekly (&amp;ldquo;Bankruptcy, prosecution and disrupted livelihoods – postmasters tell their story&amp;rdquo;) all of which is nicely summed up in Private Eye. And likewise, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a little bemused by serious business leaders being unaware that Post Office were carrying through their own prosecutions (not the Police and Crown Prosecution Service) and even more bemused that senior executive&amp;rsquo;s environmental scanning doesn&amp;rsquo;t include hearing about these media reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Privacy; Disclosure control and differential privacy</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2021-08-05-disclosure_control_privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2021-08-05-disclosure_control_privacy/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Pixabay from Pexels
I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a lot about how Differential Privacy is the answer to all our privacy concerns. However, having probed the methodology in detail, I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure. Indeed, I think we have a silo problem. Differential Privacy has been developed in a Computer Science framework as a means of balancing the need for altering data to meet privacy requirements with the need to maintain data close enough to their raw state to yield meaningful answers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
