<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configuration-Management on Insights for Action</title><link>/tags/configuration-management/</link><description>Recent content in Configuration-Management on Insights for Action</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</managingEditor><webMaster>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 15:36:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/configuration-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Some ansible woes</title><link>/tech/2020-12-18_ansible_woes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 15:36:55 +0000</pubDate><author>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</author><guid>/tech/2020-12-18_ansible_woes/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/en/tech/2020-12-18_ansible_woes/gorilla.jpeg" alt="Grumpy Gorilla">
&lt;em>Anonymous from Pinterest&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After some 12 years, I had to set up a new machine for my own use. I bought a reconditioned HP with around 16Gb RAM, 500Gb SSD. It came with a Windows OS, which I was going to wipe out. However, for various reasons (mainly some wonderful animation apps I use in teaching which require Mac or Windows only and need access to the sound system) I decided to keep the Windows host. First off, I decided to install my development machine under Vagrant/VirtualBox. I&amp;rsquo;m still fighting with VirtualBox (can&amp;rsquo;t get USB ext3 drives recognised, can&amp;rsquo;t get the sound working) and may end up having to dual boot. But apart from that, everything is wonderful. I suppose there&amp;rsquo;s a very minor inconvenience in having to logon to two computers (one real, one virtual) but that&amp;rsquo;s less hassle than dual booting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configuration management</title><link>/tech/2020_09-03_ansible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</author><guid>/tech/2020_09-03_ansible/</guid><description>&lt;p>One thing I have learnt is configuration management. It&amp;rsquo;s an under-rated aspect of reproducible research. I was quickly experimenting with an &lt;strong>R&lt;/strong> package, but needed to install the &lt;code>sf&lt;/code> package on my tinkering machine. That in turn required another &lt;strong>R&lt;/strong> package &lt;code>units&lt;/code>. And in turn, &lt;code>units&lt;/code> needed some header files, as did &lt;code>sf&lt;/code>. As it turns out, &lt;code>units&lt;/code> package failed with a very nice error message telling me exactly what I had to do. And I had very had &lt;em>deja vu&lt;/em> dealing with &lt;code>sf&lt;/code> because I know I&amp;rsquo;ve handed that before.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>