<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Public-Data on Insights for Action</title><link>/tags/public-data/</link><description>Recent content in Public-Data on Insights for Action</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</managingEditor><webMaster>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:34:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/public-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Privacy; Disclosure control and differential privacy</title><link>/posts/2021-08-05-disclosure_control_privacy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate><author>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</author><guid>/posts/2021-08-05-disclosure_control_privacy/</guid><description>&lt;script type="text/javascript"
 src="https://cdn.mathjax.org/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-AMS-MML_HTMLorMML">
&lt;/script>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/en/posts/2021-08-05-disclosure_control_privacy/pexels-pixabay-39584.jpg" alt="Data lock and chain">
&lt;em>Photo by Pixabay from Pexels&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a lot about how &lt;strong>Differential Privacy&lt;/strong> is the answer to all our privacy concerns. However, having probed the methodology in detail, I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure. Indeed, I think we have a silo problem. Differential Privacy has been developed in a Computer Science framework as a means of balancing the need for altering data to meet privacy requirements with the need to maintain data close enough to their raw state to yield meaningful answers. But I&amp;rsquo;m not convinced people working with tools from canonical Computer Science ask the same questions as people working from canonical Statistical Science (I include sociologists, demographers, public health researchers within this latter framework). So I&amp;rsquo;ve written this post as a first step to understanding the broader Differential Privacy framework. I can understand specific results for specific methods; but I just don&amp;rsquo;t see that Differential Privacy magically solves all possible trade-offs between preserving individual privacy and making data available to researchers which can answer their questions with sufficient accuracy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Sources and Cycling</title><link>/posts/2020-09-03_data_sources_on_cyling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</author><guid>/posts/2020-09-03_data_sources_on_cyling/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something I&amp;rsquo;ve been droning on about for a few years concerns our reluctance to use datasets that already exist.&lt;/p>

 &lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oMAk89KcvY4?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>Specifically in relation to cycling, we have a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of data on cycling that is rarely used, and that&amp;rsquo;s without worrying about data that aren&amp;rsquo;t disseminated in a way that lets us use it. Here are some high quality UK based data sources. These come from surveys that are &lt;strong>very&lt;/strong> expensive to conduct:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>