<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech Stack on Insights for Action</title>
    <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech Stack on Insights for Action</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 15:36:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Some ansible woes</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12-18_ansible_woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 15:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12-18_ansible_woes/</guid>
      <description>Anonymous from Pinterest
After some 12 years, I had to set up a new machine for my own use. I bought a reconditioned HP with around 16Gb RAM, 500Gb SSD. It came with a Windows OS, which I was going to wipe out. However, for various reasons (mainly some wonderful animation apps I use in teaching which require Mac or Windows only and need access to the sound system) I decided to keep the Windows host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github actions</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12-14_github_actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 15:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12-14_github_actions/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Oleg Magni from Pexels
I know this seems like a tiny problem compared to everything else that has happened in 2020. But I started the year having learnt how to use Travis CI. This meant I could put my hobby projects under some kind of continuous testing. Now, whatever the merits of various workflows that can used for CI, Travis was supported by the R community. It was well integrated into R package development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software capital</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12_01_api_contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 11:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-12_01_api_contracts/</guid>
      <description>David Sankel CppCon 2016 presentation &amp;ldquo;Building Software Capital&amp;rdquo;
Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been updating my C++ skills. In the far past, I&amp;rsquo;ve used it to speed up algorithms in scripted languages. However, I have never used it as a standalone programming language. And when I say C++ I think I really mean C, I just happen to compile it with g++. Currently, I have a couple of problems which might change my limited exposure and get me much deeper in C++ code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflicts between Agile and Data Modelling</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-11-25_agile_and_data_modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 10:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-11-25_agile_and_data_modelling/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Christina Morillo from Pexels
Having worked in various Agile and Waterfall environments I have become fascinated by the potential mismatch between Data Modelling and Agile. Searching for some discussion pieces on this, I found an interesting post that reviews a conference discussion. Ultimately, this dates from Enterprise Data World 2015, but does seem to draw on a lot of expertise from enterprise level people who have had to reconcile Data Modelling and Agile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration management</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020_09-03_ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020_09-03_ansible/</guid>
      <description>One thing I have learnt is configuration management. It&amp;rsquo;s an under-rated aspect of reproducible research. I was quickly experimenting with an R package, but needed to install the sf package on my tinkering machine. That in turn required another R package units. And in turn, units needed some header files, as did sf. As it turns out, units package failed with a very nice error message telling me exactly what I had to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Websites with Hugo and R-Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-08-18-hugo_blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-08-18-hugo_blogdown/</guid>
      <description>The current iteration of this website is a static website based on Hugo. In my opinion, there is a lot to like about static websites. I have previously used Jekyll and once upon a time coded html manually. However, modern static website generators allow a wonderful presentation. The currently styling is based upon the Terrassa theme; for me it scored highly for accessibility and mobile friendliness. The bigger issue for me though is to do data and version controlling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The right tech for the job</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-07-05_the_right_tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/tech/2020-07-05_the_right_tech/</guid>
      <description>A small trebuchet in action
This Trebuchet is a bit puny compared to the one at Warwick Castle. But it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating piece of engineering, and certainly makes a bit of a difference from doing bisections with a compass. Here&amp;rsquo;s why I selected this as &amp;ldquo;the right tech&amp;rdquo; to use in school outreach work.
This is old work now, but I learnt a lot getting involved in it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>