<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CIDC on Insights for Action</title><link>/tags/cidc/</link><description>Recent content in CIDC on Insights for Action</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</managingEditor><webMaster>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 15:22:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cidc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Github actions</title><link>/tech/2020-12-14_github_actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 15:22:41 +0000</pubDate><author>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</author><guid>/tech/2020-12-14_github_actions/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/en/tech/2020-12-16_github_actions/pexels-oleg-magni-1781622.jpg" alt="Continuous Testing">
&lt;em>Photo by Oleg Magni from Pexels&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know this seems like a tiny problem compared to everything else that has happened in 2020. But I started the year having learnt how to use Travis CI. This meant I could put my hobby projects under some kind of continuous testing. Now, whatever the merits of various workflows that can used for CI, Travis was supported by the R community. It was well integrated into R package development. Unfortunately, after an acquisition and a restructure, Travis have recently announced that they are dropping the free tier for open source projects. I have no objection to paying for a service, and certainly suspect had I been using tools like Travis for the last 15 years I would have saved myself huge amounts of time and stress. It&amp;rsquo;s possibly even more important to have CI given my development habits, which go in fits and starts depending on other commitments. I can certainly remember needing to give a live demonstration and finding out that a package upgrade had broken all my code (and to make things worse, there was no question of using an earlier version of the software on the presentation machines). That said, there are plenty of developers who feel Travis have gone back on earlier promises regarding a free tier. Whatever the rights and wrongs, the bigger issue for me is that the R package building integration will likely move away from supporting Travis as thoroughly as it does just now.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>