<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>age-period-cohort on Insights for Action</title>
    <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/tags/age-period-cohort/</link>
    <description>Recent content in age-period-cohort on Insights for Action</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 20:34:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://insightsforaction.uk/tags/age-period-cohort/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interactive time series plots</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2021-01-21_interactive_time_series/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2021-01-21_interactive_time_series/</guid>
      <description>It’s been taking a little longer than I’d wanted to collate estimates of cycle activity based on the National Travel Survey, partly because there are big gaps in the 70s and 80s before it became a continuous survey, and partly because it is a complex survey.
In the meantime, I’ve produced a “simple” time series plot of the total number of serious and fatal cycle casualties reported to the police from 1979 to 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing context; the value of historical data</title>
      <link>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2021-01-06_age_period_cohort/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insightsforaction.uk/posts/2021-01-06_age_period_cohort/</guid>
      <description>I believe that data makes little sense without context. Often, we are lacking adequate information on context. When researching disease, knowing the age and sex of the patients is almost always important. When considering road injury research, it is harder to arrive at such an understanding because firstly there are both drivers and casualties to consider, and secondly there may be more than one driver. One of the most substantial weaknesses in the official road safety collision data are that no information is collected on uninjured passengers in any of the vehicles involved.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
