<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stats19 on Insights for Action</title><link>/tags/stats19/</link><description>Recent content in Stats19 on Insights for Action</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</managingEditor><webMaster>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/stats19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fire and Rescue RTI extrications</title><link>/posts/2025_02_07-fire-and_rescue-rti-extrications-mapped/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</author><guid>/posts/2025_02_07-fire-and_rescue-rti-extrications-mapped/</guid><description>&lt;p>Again, this uses data released by the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistical-data-sets/fire-statistics-data-tables#non-dwelling-fires-attended">Home Office&lt;/a> on Fire and Rescue involvement in Road Traffic Collisions. These data are in very aggregated form, and not entirely useful for analysis. However, I’m just trying to understand the data available before I think harder about what questions you might want to ask. There is one interesting table on extrications by Fire and Rescue Service. I’ve summed the numbers for the last three years and used some ONS mid-year population estimates to create a rate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fire and Rescue RTI extrications by age/sex</title><link>/posts/2025_02_08-fire-and-rescue-extrications-age-sex/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</author><guid>/posts/2025_02_08-fire-and-rescue-extrications-age-sex/</guid><description>&lt;p>This also uses the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistical-data-sets/fire-statistics-data-tables#non-dwelling-fires-attended">Home Office&lt;/a> on Fire and Rescue involvement in Road Traffic Collisions. Again, these data are aggregated to the point they are difficult to use. But by way of understanding what’s here, I’ve tried looking at an “Extrication rate”. For each sex and age grouping, I’ve calculated the number of STATs19 reported serious casualties and used this as a denominator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fire and Rescue reporting of RTIs</title><link>/posts/2025_02_05-fire-and_rescue-reporting-rti/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</author><guid>/posts/2025_02_05-fire-and_rescue-reporting-rti/</guid><description>&lt;p>Now, it’s important to note we are talking about very different things here. In theory &lt;strong>all&lt;/strong> vehicular road collisions in which someone is injured should be reported to the police. Other services are only involved when the injuries are serious enough. But, at an aggregate level you would expect some kind of association between the number of incidents reported to the police and the number attended by the Fire and Rescue service. I’ve recently had my attention drawn to some of the data released by the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistical-data-sets/fire-statistics-data-tables#non-dwelling-fires-attended">Home Office&lt;/a> on Fire and Rescue involvement in Road Traffic Collisions. Unlike the STATs19 (Police Recorded Data) it’s very aggregate, but it is possible to make some comparisons. The following are based on Table FR904 which details the number of fatalities and casualties attended. We can do the comparisons fairly simply from 2016&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pedestrian casualties of cycle crashes</title><link>/posts/2025-01-22-pedestrian-casualties-of-cycle-crashes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>paul@insightsforaction.uk (Paul Hewson)</author><guid>/posts/2025-01-22-pedestrian-casualties-of-cycle-crashes/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are a few oddities like this lurking in the collision data that deserve more of an explanation. There are (sadly) a small number of pedestrians who are killed following a collision with a bicycle most years. But what caught my eye was the way that the number of serious injuries has been increasing over the last few years. This feels like something that deserves a better explanation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>